Hello, I'm Dr. Sheldon Cooper.
Bonjour, je suis le Dr Sheldon Cooper.
Welcome to Sheldon Cooper Presents Fun With Flags.
Bienvenue à Sheldon Cooper et Les drapeaux, c‘est fun.
Before we get started...
Pour commencer,
...l'd like to announce the winner of our "design your own flag" competition...
je voudrais annoncer le vainqueur
...but I can't.
mais c‘est impossible.
The only entry was from GameyGamer75, I know that was a JPEG of your buttocks.
Le seul participant était GameyGamer15,
Now, this week, we have a very special episode...
L'épisode de cette semaine est spécial.
...where we explore the flags of the popular entertainment franchise Star Trek.
Nous allons découvrir les drapeaux de la série Star Trek.
And to help me, I'm pleased to introduce Internet personality...
Pour cela,j'ai le plaisir d'accueillir la célèbre star
...former star of Star Trek: The Next Generation...
de Star Trek : La Nouvelle Génération
...and the only guy I know lucky enough to be immortalized in one-sixteenth scale.
et le seul homme que je connais qui a été immortalisé en miniature,
Set phasers to "fun"...
réglez vos phaseurs sur ”fun"
...for my friend Wil Wheaton.
pour mon ami, Wii Wheaton.
-Hi, thanks for having me. Happy to be here. AMY: Cut.
- Je suis heureux d'être ici. - Coupez.
-What's wrong? -Sorry, you were brilliant as always.
- Qu'est-ce qu'il y a ? - Tu es brillant comme toujours.
Wil, that was a little wooden.
Wii, c‘était un peu coincé.
-Wooden? -Don't worry, it wasn't terrible.
- Coincé ? - Ce n‘était pas horrible.
Just this time, try to say it the way people sound.
Essaye d'être plus naturel.
And action.
Action.
My friend Wil Wheaton.
Mon ami, Wii Wheaton.
Hi, thanks for having me. I'm excited to be here.
Merci, je suis ravi d'être ici.
-So, Wil, what do you have for us first? -Well, this is an exciting one.
- Qu'est-ce que tu as en stock ? - Quelque chose de formidable.
This is the flag of the United Federation of Planets.
Le drapeau de la Fédération des planètes unies.
-Now, what's interesting about this flag-- AMY: Cut.
- Ce drapeau est intéressant car... - Coupez.
-What was wrong with that? -lt's called Fun With Flags.
- Quel est le problème ? - C'est Les drapeaux, c‘est fun.
They're not at half-mast. Nobody died. Let's try and keep it upbeat.
Ils ne sont pas en berne. Un peu d'entrain.
I can handle a web show without a lot of direction.
Je sais comment présenter une série Internet.
SHELDON: It's true.
C'est vrai.
In 1982 Wil played the voice of Martin the mouse in The Secret ofNIMH.
En 1982, Wii a prêté sa voix a la souris du Secret ofNIMH.
You moved me.
Trés émouvant.
You'll have to forgive me.
Tu devras m'excuser.
This is my first time directing. I just want it to be good.
Ce sont mes débuts de réalisatrice. Je veux faire du bon boulot.
-So do I. AMY: Great.
- Moi aussi. - Génial.
So this time, let's try more real boy, less Pinocchio.
Cette fois—ci, soit plus naturel, moins Pinocchio.
-And action. -And cut.
- Action. - Coupez.
You realize I'm doing this for free, right?
Tu sais que je ne suis pas payé ?
Yes, and so far, we're still not getting our money's worth.
Et pour le moment je n'en ai pas pour mon argent.
Let's try it again.
Essayons encore une fois.
Everybody's having fun.
Faites comme si vous vous amusiez.
And action.
Action.
So, Wil...
Wii,
...what do you have for us first?
que vas-tu nous montrer ?
Well, this is an exciting one.
Quelque chose de formidable.
This is the flag of the United Federation of Planets.
Voici le drapeau de la Fédération des planètes unies.
Cut.
Coupez.
Problem, first-time director?
Un problème, réalisatrice débutante ?
None that I could see.
Pas pour moi.
I saw a man who loved flags almost as much as I do.
Je vois que tu aimes les drapeaux autant que moi.
I got goose bumps.
J'en ai la chair de poule.
-He was overacting on purpose. -Really?
- Il surjouait. - Vraiment ?
Oh, he reminded me of a young William Shatner.
Il me rappelait William Shatner, jeune.
I'm really happy to do this for you...
Je veux bien te rendre service,
...but not if she's gonna be a huge pain in the ass the whole time.
mais pas si elle va continuer a m‘enquiquiner tout le temps.
Are you gonna let him speak to me like that?
Tu le laisses me parler comme ça ?
Well...
Eh bien...
...you're my girlfriend, and I don't want you to be upset.
Tu es ma copine, etje ne veux pas que tu sois fâchée.
Then again, Wil Wheaton's my friend, and I don't want him to be upset.
Mais Wii Wheaton est un ami etje ne veux pas qu'il soit fâché.
This is a sticky wicket.
C'est épineux.
What do you think?
Qu'en penses—tu ?
Can I speak to you for a second?
Je peux te parler une minute ?
I'll be right back.
Je reviens tout de suite.
Feel free to play with yourself.
Tu peux te tripoter.
I don't care for your friend, and he's being rude to me.
Je n'aime pas ton ami, il me manque de respect.
You need to ask him to leave.
Demande—lui de partir.
Amy, I can't just ask Wil Wheaton to leave.
Je ne peux pas demander a Wii Wheaton de partir.
He's a minor celebrity.
C'est une célébrité mineure.
Once you explain who he is, many people recognize him.
Lorsque les gens savent qui il est, ils le reconnaissent.
Fine, then maybe I should go.
Alors, c‘est moi qui pars.
Could you? That would solve everything.
Vraiment ? Ça résoudrait tout.
You are the best. I'll see you at dinner tonight?
Tu es super. On dîné ensemble ce soir ?
Sure you wouldn't rather have dinner with your friend Wil Wheaton?
Tu ne préférerais pas dîner avec ton ami Wii Wheaton ?
Come to think of it, I would.
Maintenant que j'y pense, si.
You, little lady, are on fire.
Toi, ma petite, tu es incroyable.
Every time we eat here, your mom refuses to let me help with the dishes.
Quand on dîné ici, ta mère refuse mon aide pour la vaisselle.
Don't take it personally.
Oublié.
She likes doing them by herself so she can lick the plates with no one looking.
Elle aime la faire seule pour lécher les assiettes en cachette.
You ready to go?
Tu es prêt ?
Yeah, let me just grab a couple of fresh turtlenecks.
Oui, je veux juste prendre quelques pulls à col roulé.
I don't understand why you keep your stuff here when there's room at home.
Pourquoi gardes-tu tes affaires ici ? On ala place àla maison.
What are you talking about?
De quoi tu parles ?
All I have here is a few sweaters, books, bank stuff...
Tout ce que j'ai ici, c‘est quelques pulls, quelques livres,
...computers, mail, collectibles, medicine and my electric body groomer.
des ordinateurs, des souvenirs, des pilules et mon épilateur.
Ooh! There's my plaid dickey.
Voici mon plastron écossais.
Oh. Got this at the Goodwill store for 50 cents. Can you believe it? Heh.
Je l'ai trouvé à l‘Armée du Salut pour 50 centimes.
Fifty cents sounds right.
C'est le juste prix.
-Let's go. -You know, it's kind of late.
- Allons-y. - Il se fait tard.
-Why don't we spend the night here? -Because we don't live here.
- Si on passait la nuit ici ? - On ne vit pas ici.
-I know. -Do you?
- Je sais. - Vraiment ?
You said when you got back from space...
Tu m‘avais dit qu'à ton retour de l'espace
...you were gonna move into my apartment, but half the time we stay here.
tu emménagerais avec moi, mais on passe la moitié du temps ici.
That's not true.
Ce n‘est pas vrai.
MRS. WOLOWITZ: Howard, I'm doing laundry! You want me to put anything in for you?!
Je vais faire une lessive! Tu as des vêtements à laver ?
There's some underwear in the hamper!
J'ai quelques caleçons au sale.
MRS. WOLOWITZ: Oh, good, I got that new stain stick to try out!
Parfait, je vais pouvoir essayer ce nouveau détachant.
Thank you. I only put it on the list two weeks ago!
Merci. Je l‘avais mis sur la liste il y a seulement deux semaines!
Okay, I see what you're getting at.
Je comprends ce que tu veux dire.
How about this weekend, I'll box up all my things...
Ce week-end, je fais mes cartons
...and move them to our place?
etj'emménage tout chez nous.
Thank you.
Merci.
The lightsabers will look great in the living room.
Les sabres lumineux iront bien dans le salon.
Or in the closet. We can decide later.
Ou dans le placard. On en discutera plus tard.
MRS. WOLOWITZ: Howard, help! My hand's stuck in the garbage disposal!
A l'aide ! Ma main est coincée dans l'évier !
Just let go of whatever piece of food you're holding!
Lâche ce que tu tiens dans la main !
MRS. WOLOWITZ: Are you kidding?! It's a perfectly good chicken leg!
Tu plaisantes ! C'est une cuisse de poulet toute fraîche !
Hey, look who's out after dark like a big boy.
Regarde qui sort la nuit comme un grand garçon.
l was out raising heck with Mr. Wil Wheaton.
J‘étais de sortie avec Wii Wheaton.
Four hours more and we would have closed down the HomeTown Buffet.
On aurait presque pu faire la fermeture de HomeTown Buffet.
-I thought you had plans with Amy. -Yeah, I did.
- Tu n‘étais pas avec Amy ? - C'était prévu.
But then Wil called Amy a pain in the A-S-S.
Mais Wii l‘a traitée d‘enquiquineuse.
She got huffy and left, and then Wil and I headed out to dinner.
Elle est partie fâchée, et Wii et moi sommes allés dîner.
That place really did remind me of my hometown.
Ce restaurant me rappelait mon village.
Because there we also have a HomeTown Buffet.
Lai-bas aussi, il y a un HomeTown Buffet.
-Hold on. Wil and Amy had an argument? -Yes, quite the kerfuffle.
- Wii et Amy se sont disputés ? - Oui.
-Then Amy got mad and left? -Walked right out the door.
- Amy s'est énervée et est partie ? - En claquant la porte.
And you...?
Ettoi...
Enjoyed a delightful dinner at a reasonable price.
J'ai eu un bon dîner à un prix raisonnable.
The manager recognized Wil and let us sit right next to the frozen-yogurt machine.
Le gérant a reconnu Wii
Right next to it.
Juste à côté.
l was closer to it than I am to you right now.
Encore plus proche que ça.
-Buddy, I think Amy might be upset. -Why's that?
- Amy doit être fâchée. - Pourquoi ça ?
Because your friend was rude to her and then you went to dinner with him.
Parce que ton ami l‘a insultée et que tu as choisi de dîner avec lui.
You're just repeating what I said.
Tu répétes ce que je Viens de dire.
It's like living with a lactose-intolerant parrot.
Tu es comme un perroquet intolérant au lactose.
Trust me. Call her.
Fais—moi confiance. Appelle—la.
Fine.
D‘accord.
It's a shame you didn't go to dinner with us...
Dommage que tu n'aies pas dîné avec nous,
...because the buffet you're about to enjoy only serves humble pie...
parce que la dose d'humilité que je vais te servir
...a dessert much less tasty than frozen yogurt.
est bien moins délicieuse qu‘une boule de glace.
l was this close.
Juste à côté.
What?
Quoi ?
You'll appreciate this.
Ça va te plaire.
Leonard has some ridiculous notion that you're mad at me.
Leonard pense que tu es fâchée avec moi.
Tell him you're not mad at me. Go ahead, set him straight.
Dis—lui que tu n'es pas fâchée. Rétablis les faits.
I'm mad at you, Sheldon.
Je suis fâchée avec toi.
Eat one of your Luna Bars.
Mange une de tes barres.
Very often, when women think they're angry, they're reallyjust hungry.
Souvent les femmes croient être en colère quand elles ont faim.
I'm not hungry.
Je n‘ai pas faim.
Your friend insulted me and you didn't do anything.
Ton ami étai! impoli et tu n'as rien fait.
Precisely. I didn't do anything.
Exactement. Je n'ai rien fait.
Now, does someone feel like checking her emotional math?
Tu veux vérifier ton quotient émotionnel ?
Keep going, buddy. You're doing great.
Continue. Tu t‘en sors trés bien.
Sheldon, I'm your girlfriend and you should have taken my side.
Tu es mon copain et tu aurais dû être de mon côté.
That's it. End of story. Good night.
C‘est tout. Fin de l‘histoire. Bonne nuit.
Wow, Amy's mad and Leonard was right.
Amy est fâchée et Leonard a raison.
What a weird day.
Quelle journée bizarre.
Hey, sorry this took so long. But you used to work here.
Désolée pour l'attente. Mais tu travaillais ici.
-You know how it is. -Kitchen slammed again?
- Tu sais ce que c'est. - Du retard en cuisine ?
No, I'm a terrible waitress, remember?
Non, je suis la pire des serveuses.
So anything I can do to help you move tomorrow?
Je peux t‘aider à déménager demain ?
Now that you mention it, I was thinking tomorrow might not be great.
Puisqu'on en parle,
-What's your excuse this time? -No excuse.
- Quelle est ton excuse cette fois ? - Ce n‘est pas une excuse.
It's just, you know, I'm Jewish...
C'estjuste que je suis juif
...and technically, we're not supposed to drive or carry anything on the Sabbath...
etje ne dois ni conduire ni porter quoi que ce soit pendant Shabbat,
...so this one's on God.
donc, c‘est la faute de Dieu.
That might be more convincing if you didn't have a mouthful of bacon cheeseburger.
Tu serais plus convaincant
My religion's kind of loosey-goosey, you know.
Ma religion est compliquée.
As long as you got your schmeckel clipped and don't wear a cross, you're good.
Tant que ton schmeckel est coupé
Howie, you promised you'd move.
Tu avais promis de déménager.
-And I will. -Yeah, right.
- Je vais le faire. - C'est ça.
I'm not going to live in my mother's house for the rest of my life. I'm not a child.
Je ne vais pas Vivre chez ma mére toute ma vie.
I've seen her burp you.
Elle te fait faire ton rot.
She did not burp me.
Pas vraiment.
She was patting me on the back and I happened to burp.
Elle me caressait le dos et il s'est trouvé que j'ai roté.
Don't you have other tables you should be waiting on?
Tu n'as pas d'autres tables à t‘occuper ?
Yeah, but I told you, I'm not good at myjob.
Comme j'ai dit, je suis une mauvaise serveuse.
-Listen to me. He is never gonna leave. -l'm starting to think you're right.
- Ecoute-moi. Il ne partirajamais. - Je commence a y croire.
All right, I've had enough of this. I'm a grown man. I have a successful career.
Ça suffit. Je suis un adulte. Ma carrière est une réussite.
I mean, for the love of God, I've been to space.
Je suis même allé dans l‘espace.
lwill move out when I'm ready, and I don't need anyone badgering me into it.
Je déménagerai quand je serai prêt. Je n'ai pas besoin qu'on me harcèle.
That was just for her benefit. I'll move tomorrow. I love you. Don't leave me.
C'était pour elle. Je déménage demain. Je t‘aime. Ne me quitte pas.
Angry Amy?
Amy fâchée ?
What?
Quoi ?
I've been thinking about what happened, and I hope this gift will make things better.
J'ai réfléchi à ce qui s'est passé, etj'espére que tu aimeras ce cadeau.
Star Trek DVDs?
Des DVD de Star Trek ?
Why would I want this?
Pour quoi faire ?
First of all, you're welcome.
Tout d'abord, de rien.
Furthermore, not being familiar with Wil Wheaton's body of work...
Comme tu ne connaissais pas l'œuvre de Wii Wheaton,
...there was no way for you to know you were being rude to a national treasure.
tu ne pouvais pas savoir que tu étais impolie
Get ready for 130 hours of "I told you so."
Prépare—toi pour 130 heures de ”je te l‘avais dit."
Fine, I'll just tell you what happens.
Bon, je te raconte l‘histoire.
Episode one, "Encounter at Farpoint."
Premier épisode, ”Rendez-vous à Farpoint."
Fade in.
Fondu ouvert.
The new Enterprise heads out on its maiden voyage...
L'Enlerprise part pour son voyage initiatique
...to contact the Bandi people of Deneb IV.
pour contacter le peuple Bandi de Deneb IV.
Enter Wesley Crusher, played by my buddy--
Arrive Wesley Crusher, interprété par...
She's hooked.
Elle est accro.
Wow, an end of an era.
C'est la fin d‘une époque.
Boy, if these walls could talk.
Si ces murs pouvaient parler.
They'd say, "Why does he touch himself so much?"
Ils diraient: ”Pourquoi se tripote-t-il autant ?"
I can't believe I'm not gonna live here anymore.
Je n'arrive pas a y croire.
This has always been my bedroom.
C'est ma chambre depuis toujours.
Right here is where my mom used to mark my height.
C'est la que ma mère me mesurait.
"Fifth grade, sixth grade, seventh grade, eighth grade, ninth grade."
“Sixième, cinquième, quatrième, troisième, seconde."
Yeah, I remember when l was 5...
Je me souviens quand j‘avais cinq ans,
...hiding under this desk with all my Halloween candy.
je me cachais sous ce bureau avec mes friandises d‘Halloween.
Had some Peanut M&M's...
Avec des M&M aux cacahuètes.
...went into my first anaphylactic shock, had to be rushed to the hospital...
Mon premier choc anaphylactique, j'ai dû aller à l‘hôpital.
...came home, celebrated with a Snickers, went into my second anaphylactic shock.
En rentrant, un Snickers a provoqué mon second choc anaphylactique.
When did you figure out you're allergic to nuts?
Quand as-tu découvert ton allergie aux noix ?
Sometime around the third Almond Joy.
Après mon troisième Almond Joy.
Okay, wanna start loading this stuff into the truck?
On commence à charger le camion ?
Yeah, I guess.
J'imagine.
Hey, would you do me a favor? Go on ahead.
Vous voulez me rendre service ? Allez—y d'abord.
I just want one last moment alone in my old room.
J'ai besoin d'un moment seul dans ma chambre.
We're not standing outside by the U-Haul while you fondle yourself.
On ne va pas t'attendre pendant que tu te tripotes.
Fine, let's go.
Allons-y.
Hey, what brings you in?
Que viens-tu faire ici ?
Penny, if you wouldn't mind, I'd like to have a conversation about girls.
J'aimerais qu'on parle de filles.
Had a feeling we'd have a talk like this sooner or later.
Je pensais bien que ça finirait par arriver.
Are you finally getting fuzz in weird places?
Tu commences à avoir du duvet dans des endroits étranges ?
Penny, please, I'm on the horns of a relationship dilemma.
Je suis face a un dilemme.
And for the record, I had a full pubis of hair by the time I was 19.
Je dois dire que j‘avais tous mes poils pubiens a 19 ans.
And for the record:
Etje voudrais juste mentionner:
-So, what are you drinking? -Well, it's been a rough day.
- Qu'est-ce que tu bois ? - Lajournée a été longue.
I usually go chamomile tea, but I don't think that's gonna cut it.
En général,je bois une camomille, mais ça ne suffira pas.
You could have a Long Island iced tea.
Tu pourrais prendre un punch au thé.
Will that calm my nerves?
Ça me détendra ?
It's calmed the pants off me a couple times.
Ça m‘a détendu quelquefois au point d'en oublier ma culotte.
-Sold. -Oh.
Parfait.
So the heart you got from the wizard giving you trouble?
Le cœur que t'a donné le magicien te donne du fil à retordre ?
The trouble isn't with me, Penny, it's with your gender.
Ce n‘est pas moi le problème, c‘est le sexe faible.
Someday scientists will discover...
La science découvrira un jour
...that second X chromosome contains nothing but nonsense and twaddle.
que le second chromosome X ne contient
Yeah, Amy told me what happened.
Amy m‘a raconté.
Look, just apologize. It'll warm her twaddle.
Excuse-toi, ça fera fondre ses inepties.
That's a Band-Aid at best.
Ça les réchauffera a peine.
The core problem is that Amy and Wil do not like each other...
Le problème, c‘est qu‘Amy et Wii ne s'aiment pas,
...which is baffling because they're both crazy about me.
ce qui est d'autant plus choquant qu‘ils m‘adorent tous les deux.
And I like them, which indicates they're bright and interesting...
Je les aime, ce qui signifie qu‘ils sont intelligents et intéressants
...andlor were on Star Trek.
etlou qu‘ils étaient dans Star Trek.
Honey, you can't make people like each other.
Tu ne peux pas forcer les gens à s'aimer.
Not true. Leonard made me like you.
Faux, Leonard m‘a forcé à t‘aimer.
Let me tell you, that was a hard row to hoe.
Ça a été une longue couleuvre à avaler.
Cheers, pal.
A ta santé.
Boy, that is a treat that's hard to beat.
Ça a du retour.
Get the Mad Hatter on the horn. I'm having a tea party.
Préviens Ie Chapelier fou, c‘est l‘heure du thé.
You might wanna pace yourself.
Vas—y mollo.
I drink tea all the time. I think I know what I'm doing.
Je bois du thé tout le temps. Je sais ce que je fais.
Far be it for me to criticize a man with a full pubis.
Je ne saurais critiquer un homme qui a une toison pubienne.
Look, your problem is not Wil Wheaton. Your problem is the way you treated Amy.
Wii Wheaton n‘est pas le problème. C'est la façon dont tu as traité Amy.
Problem is I'm out of tea.
Le problème, c‘est que je n'ai plus de thé.
Come on, someone insulted your girlfriend, you just let him do it?
Quelqu'un insulte ta copine, et tu le laisses faire ?
Thought you Texas guys stood up for your womenfolk.
Je pensais que les Texans avaient plus d‘honneur.
Oh, Penny, please.
Je t‘en prie.
Think I've evolved beyond my simple rustic upbringing.
Je suis plus évolué que ça.
Sorry.
Désolée.
On the other hand, that low-down polecat done wronged my woman.
Mais d'un autre côté, ce bouseux a mal traité ma femme.
Welcome to Long Island, Tex.
Bienvenue à Long Island.
Amy deserves better.
Amy mérite mieux que ça.
You know, when we buy the Planters Deluxe Mix...
Quand on achète un sac de noix assorties,
...she eats all the Brazil nuts so I don't have to look at them.
elle mange toutes les noix du Brésil pour me les cacher.
She's a unique blend of saint and squirrel.
Elle est un mélange entre une sainte et un écureuil.
Yup, that she is. Here you go.
Exactement.
I'm a callous egomaniac. She's gonna leave me.
Je suis tellement égocentrique. Elle va me quitter.
-No, she won't. -No, she won't. I'm great.
- Non. - Non. Je suis trop génial.
Okay, I have now officially moved out of my mother's house.
Je Viens officiellement de déménager dela maison de ma mére.
You are now the only woman in my life who I'll see naked in the bathroom.
Tu seras la seule femme de ma vie nue dans la salle de bain.
I know this wasn't easy. You doing okay?
Je sais que ce n‘était pas facile. Ça va ?
Well, I'm fine. It's just her I'm worried about.
Ça va. Je me fais du souci pour elle.
-She'll be okay. She's a grown woman. -I know.
- Elle ira bien. C'est une adulte. - Je sais.
It's just ever since my dad left, I've felt responsible for her.
Mais depuis que mon père nous a laissés,
That's a lot for a kid to deal with.
C'est beaucoup pour un enfant.
She was just so sad all the time.
Elle était tout le temps triste.
l was the only person who could cheer her up.
J‘étais le seul a pouvoir lui remonter le moral.
Well, me and Ben and Jerry.
Moi et Ben and Jerry.
She's lucky you were there.
Elle a eu dela chance de t‘avoir.
You know, she's why I first got into magic.
C'est pour elle que j'ai appris la magie.
I would do little shows for her.
Je lui faisais des tours.
Hang up a bedsheet like it was a curtain, put on a top hat and cape.
J'accrochais un drap en guise de rideau,
And partway through the act, I would say I needed a volunteer from the audience...
Et pendant le tour,
...to be my beautiful assistant and invite her up on-stage.
pourjouer le rôle de ma belle assistante,
I can still remember the way she'd smile.
Je me souviens encore de son sourire.
For a few minutes, she'd forget how lonely she was.
Elle oubliait, quelques instants, a quel point elle était seule.
Aw, crap. Let's go.
Mince. Allons-y.
Where are we going?
On va où ?
Grab a box. We'll sleep at your mother's place tonight.
Prends un carton. On dormira chez ta mère ce soir.
No, but I want to live here.
Non, je veux Vivre ici.
Well, you should've thought of that before you told me the stupid magic-trick story.
Alors, fallait pas me raconter ta stupide histoire de magie.
Can't we talk about this?
On peut au moins en discuter ?
No husband of mine is gonna break his mother's heart.
Mon mari ne brisera pas le cœur de sa mère.
Wait, how many was that?
Ça en faisait combien ?
-Hey, Sheldon, what's up? -Wouldn't you like to know.
- Sheldon, comment vas-tu ? - Ce n‘est pas tes oignons.
-Have you been drinking? -Just tea.
- Tu as bu ? - Seulement du thé.
It was the best tea I've ever had.
Le meilleur thé que j‘aie jamais bu.
Why are you here?
Pourquoi es-tu ici ?
I'll tell you.
Je vais te le dire.
I'm from Texas.
Je suis texan.
Need I say more?
Ai-je besoin d'en dire plus ?
Yeah, actually, a little more would be helpful.
Un peu plus, ça serait utile.
You insulted my woman. I'm here to defend her honor.
Tu as insulté ma femme. Je suis ici pour défendre son honneur.
Two. It was two.
Deux. Ça en faisait deux.
Now prepare yourself for what may come.
Prépare—toi pour ce qui va suivre.
Oh, Sheldon, do you really think we're gonna fight?
Tu penses vraiment qu'on va se battre ?
My fists are not up here because I'm milking a giant invisible cow.
Je n'ai pas levé mes poings pour traire une vache géante invisible.
They're up to beat an apology out of you.
Ils vont te faire cracher des excuses.
Okay, I'm sorry.
Je suis désolé.
Well, that was a long bus ride for not very much.
C'était un long trajet en bus pour peu de chose.
Are you okay?
- Tu vas bien ? - Tu poses beaucoup de questions.
As a matter of idle curiosity...
Juste par curiosité,
...which of your shrubberies do you feel would benefit from a thorough vomiting?
lequel de tes buissons bénéficierait de mon vomi ?
Never mind, I'll choose.
Ne t‘en fais pas, je vais choisir.
You were so good in Stand by Me.
Tu étais tellement bon dans Stand by Me.
Hello, I'm Dr. Sheldon Cooper.
Bonjour, je suis le Dr Sheldon Cooper.
Welcome to Sheldon Cooper Presents Fun With Flags.
Bienvenue a Sheldon Cooper présente Les drapeaux, c‘est fun.
Get ready for a very special episode...
L'émission d‘aujourd‘hui est très Spéciale.
...where we explore the flags of the popular entertainment franchise Star Trek.
Nous allons discuter des drapeaux de la célèbre série Star Trek.
And to help us, I'm pleased to introduce a special guest.
Et pour cela, j'ai le plaisir d'accueillir notre invité spécial.
Surprisingly, it only took gas money and the promise of free food to get him here.
Il a suffi de lui promettre un repas et le prix de l'essence.
Mr. LeVar Burton.
M. LeVar Burton.
Hey, Sheldon. It's a pleasure to be here.
C'est un plaisir d'être ici.
-Well, we've got some interesting flags-- -Cut.
- Les drapeaux sont intéressants... - Coupez.
Yikes, this guy is worse than Wil Wheaton.
Mon Dieu, ce mec est encore pire que Wii Wheaton.
I don't know what she's talking about, but I'm obligated to agree with her.
Je ne vois pas ce qu'elle veut dire, mais je dois être d'accord.
-She's my girlfriend. -Ah. I hear you, brother.
- C'est ma copine. - Je te comprends.
I still get lunch, right?
J'ai toujours droit au déjeuner gratuit ?
[English - us - an]
[French]